NUTTANEE KNIGHT - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

NYC, NY | 646-953-5254 | nuttaneeknight@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Over a decade of experience in hospitality management and marketing. Including increasing sales by utilizing SEO and creating social media content.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery, Python 3, *Backend:* Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code, ServiceNow

Self-directed Training: TypeScript, Python

Additional Skills: SEO, WordPress, Square Space, Event Planning, Bookkeeping (intuit), Microsoft Excel.

Languages: English, Thai, Japanese

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Restaurant Reservation Application | Thinkful | Link

08/2022

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.

Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

Library Application | Thinkful | Link

08/2022

- Assembled the functionality for an application that allows users to search, review and check out books.
- Created search and sorting functions to allow users to know what books were available and their rating.
- Coded using JavaScript functions built to enable the expansion of the library with little need for code refactoring.

Technology: JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap, HTML5, Node.js

Study Tool Application | Thinkful | Link

08/2022

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, and edit a deck of study cards.
- Defined routes and URLs, and useState over multiple components.

Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

Encryption/Decryption Application | Thinkful | Link

08/2022

- Built to be an encryption/decryption application to communicate and read top-secret messages.
- Created utilizing the test-driven development method.

Technology: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, Node.js, Bootstrap, Mocha, Chai.

Movie Database Application | Thinkful | Link

08/2022

- Assembled the back end of a movie website, allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.

Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lower Hudson Regional Information Center (SWBOCES)

Harrison, NY

03/2022 - Present

ServiceNow Admin/Developer

Revise, maintain, and update existing program in web based software application, ServiceNow.

- Develop, test and deploy custom application per user's or district's requirements.
- Collaborate with different teams to understand requirements and implement into ServiceNow solution.
- Create documentation, video content, training material and training session for system users on how to use ServiceNow.
- Participate in the implementation of ServiceNow upgrades and patches, ensuring a smooth transition.
- Implement agile methodology, create epic, story, and sprint to deploy new application in a timely manner.

Sleepy Hollow, NY

Supervisor / Head Bartender

- 04/2021 Present
- Create seasonal cocktails with the current season's inspired ingredients, increasing the sales by 25%.
- Strategize cost control with the Manager and Distributors during the supply chain crisis from COVID-19.
- Manage inventory to ensure the menu consistency and maintain the mark-up within 33%.
- Manage a 70-seat waterfront restaurant by the Hudson River, on days that the General Manager is off duty.

Atria Senior Living

Rye Brook, NY

Restaurant Coordinator 08/2020 - 07/2021

- Enforced the CDC guidelines during the lock-down of COVID-19 and ensured the residents' wellbeing.
- Worked with the residents' family to meet the residence's dietary needs.
- Coordinated the meal delivery with the staff during the lock-down for 70 rooms estate.
- Constructed a daily report for all directors.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Online

Certificate, Software Engineering

08/2022 - 01/2022

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5, CSS3,
 React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with and learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

Assumption University of Thailand

Bangkok, Thailand

Bachelor of Business Administration, Management

05/2008